《生活大爆炸》  前情提要
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
我们现在正式宣布你们成为夫妻
We now pronounce you husband and wife!
我爱死这部分了
I love this part!
我也爱
Me, too!
我内心五味杂陈啊
I have strongly mixed feelings!
霍华德真的上太空啦
So, Howard's really in space, huh?
对啊  在国际太空站呢
Mm-hmm, International Space Station.
在我们头上250英里外
250 miles that way.
此时此刻  霍华德正从上方俯视这星球
Right now, Howard's staring down at our planet
像一个小版的犹太希腊神
like a tiny Jewish Greek god.
沃罗威宙斯
Zeusowitz.
我不得不承认
I must admit,
我心里实在是有点小嫉妒
I can't help but feel a twinge of envy.
他只需往窗外一看
He can look out the window
壮丽宏伟的宇宙
and see the majesty of the universe
便尽收眼底
unfolding before his eyes.
尽收他那浑浊愚昧的眼底
His dim, uncomprehending eyes.
就像放在机场宠物运输箱里的猫
It's like a cat in an airport carrying case.
其实在太空也没这么好啦
You know, it's not exactly glamorous up there.
宇航员所喝的水
The water that the astronauts drink
都是过滤其他宇航员的尿得来的
is made from each other's recycled urine.
感觉一定不错
Must be nice.
我身上排出的各种液体都没人想要
Nobody wants anything that comes out of me.
真好奇此时此刻他在太空干嘛
I wonder what he's doing right this very second.
在零重力的状态下做实验
Mm, conducting experiments in zero gravity.
透过望远镜看着宇宙的生成
Peering through his telescope at the birth of the cosmos.
无论是什么  他的生活再也不同了
Whatever it is, we know his life will never be the same.
霍华德  你听得到我吗
Howard! Can you hear me?!
不用打电话我都能听到你在地球吼
I can hear you without the phone!
别这么暴躁
Don't be snippy.
我只是很兴奋能跟我小宝贝说话
I'm just excited to talk to my baby!
我也很兴奋啊
I'm excited to talk to you, too.
有个疯狂的谣言说你要搬走
So, what's this mishegas about you moving out
去跟那个波兰妞同居是怎么回事
to go live with the little Polish girl?!
你就不能称呼她为我老婆吗
How about calling her my wife?
老婆才不会害人家母子分离
Wives don't take boys from their mothers.
就是因为她们会  所以才要娶她们
They do. That's why we marry them!
我只希望在你回来之前
I just hope I'm not dead from a broken heart
我没有心碎而亡
before you get back.
妈  别这样
Ma, please.
太空总署的人都在听我们讲电话
Everyone from NASA is listening to this phone call.
很好  这样他们就知道你有多不孝了
Good. They should know what a horrible son you are!
好啦  妈  下次再聊  挂啦
Okay, Ma, great talking to you! Gotta go!
太空之旅  被毁得一干二净
Well... space is ruined.
好兴奋哦
This is so exciting.
我唇上的汗毛很快会跟我美丽好友一样
Soon, my upper lip will be the same fake blonde
有着好看的假金色了
as my beautiful best friend.
我天生就是这个色
Hey, this is my natural hair color.
好吧  现在
Now.
谢尔顿有替你们俩明晚
So, does Sheldon have anything special
做什么特殊安排吗
planned for you tomorrow night?
当然有  根据恋爱协议
Oh, yes. According to the Relationship Agreement,
我们的首次约会周年纪念日
on the anniversary of our first date,
他得带我去吃顿好的
he must take me to a nice dinner,
关心我那天的生活琐事
ask about my day
然后对我做出一些肢体接触
and engage in casual physical contact
是让旁观者都觉得我们很亲密的那种哦
that a disinterested onlooker might mistake for intimacy.
香艳火辣啊
That's hot.
记得使用"防护措施"哦
You kids better use protection.
这得等多久
How long does this stay on?
就几分钟吧
Just a couple of minutes.
你以前没试过染汗毛吗
You've really never done this before?
高中时候试过一次  后来打盹
Once in high school, but I dozed off
醒来之后  我脸上就二级化学灼伤了
and woke up with second-degree chemical burns on my face.
天啊  那也太惨了吧
Oh, my gosh, that's awful.
其他同学有取笑你吗
The other kids make fun of you?
没有  我编了借口
No, I had a cover story;
我说那是疱疹[性病]
I told everyone it was herpes.
那你跟莱纳德一切如何啊
So, how's everything going with you and Leonard?
不知道  还是有点怪
I don't know, it's still kind of weird.
他上次的做爱中乱求婚的事
We haven't really recovered since he proposed to me
我们还没缓过来
in the middle of sex.
你倒好
Oh. Boo-hoo.
要是谢尔顿在我们做爱的时候求婚
If Sheldon proposed to me during sex,
我的子宫一定会紧紧夹住他那里
my ovaries would grab on to him
不放他走
and never let go.
莱纳德  你同不同意人择原理
Leonard, where do you stand on the anthropic principle?
这问题有意思
Interesting question.
一方面来说  我一直...
On the one hand, I always thought...
你根本就不知道那是什么  对吧
You don't even know what it is, do you?
人择原理指出如果我们想解释
The anthropic principle states that if we wish to explain
为何宇宙是我们看到的这种样子
why our universe exists the way it does,
那会是因为它必须像现在这样
the answer is that it must have qualities
演化出能问出这道问题的智慧生物
that allow intelligent creatures to arise
才会有这个问题的出现
who are capable of asking the question.
而我现在就正问着这问题呢
As I am doing so eloquently right now.
我知道人择原理是什么
I know what the anthropic principle is.
当然啊  我刚给你解释完
Of course. I just explained it to you.
那你是同意还是反对呢
Now, where do you stand on it?
-你同意吗  -非常同意
- Where do you stand on it? - Strongly pro.
那我就相信是神花了六天创世
Then I believe that God created the world in six days,
然后在第七天  造了你来烦我
and on the seventh, he made you to annoy me.
你们俩好啊
Hey, guys.
对了  拉杰
Yeah, wait, Raj,
你同不同意人择原理呢
where do you stand on the anthropic principle?
-完全同意  -好孩子
- I'm all for it. - Attaboy!
等等  为什么你觉得他懂
Well, hang on. Why do you believe
而我不懂什么是人择原理呢
that he knows what it is and I don't?
莱纳德  还是别了吧
Oh, Leonard. Let's not take a saw
这说出来多伤感情啊
to the branch we're sitting on, shall we?
你们俩如果今晚有空
Hey, uh, if you guys are free tonight,
我听说有家SPA  你可以一边泡脚
I heard about a SPA where you soak your feet
水里还会有小鱼
in a pool full of little fish
帮你吃掉你脚上的死皮哦
that eat all the dead skin right off them.
不用我说你们也知道  在洛杉矶
I don't need to tell you, in Los Angeles,
全年都是拖鞋季
sandal season is year round.
-其实我跟佩妮有约了  -好吧
- Actually, I'm hanging out with Penny. - Oh, okay.
那就剩咱俩去了  谢尔顿
Sounds like it's me and you, Sheldon.
一起去让小鱼帮我们打磨一下脚吧
How about we sic some guppies on those puppies?
我说过无数次了
As I've stated before on numerous occasions,
我唯一能接受被它吃掉的海洋生物
the only sea creature I would even consider being eaten by
就是北海巨妖
is the Kraken,
因为我死前听到的最后一句话是
because the last words I would hear are:
"放北海巨妖"[电影《诸神之战》台词]
"Release the Kraken."
这句话百听不厌
That never gets old.
"放北海巨妖"
"Release the Kraken!"
好怕怕哟
Oh, chills.
再说了  我要跟艾米吃晚餐
Besides, I'm having dinner with Amy.
好吧  那我回家一个人待着好了
Oh, okay. I'll just go home and be alone.
这样也蛮好
W-Which is cool.
我一个人吃  一个人睡  一个人默默流泪
I eat alone, I sleep alone, I cry alone, so...
蛮好
Cool.
真可惜
Darn.
如果你不忙  我还想请你跟我们一起晚餐呢
If you weren't busy, I'd ask you to join us.
真的吗  我可以去吗  谢谢
Really? I can come? Thanks!
谢尔顿  你跟艾米的约会之夜
Sheldon, are you sure you want to be bringing Raj
你确定要带拉杰去吗
on your date night with Amy?
当然
Oh, absolutely.
根据契约规定  我得跟艾米聊天
I have a contractual obligation to provide Amy with conversation
并有肢体接触
and casual physical contact,
但是没有地方明确指出
but nowhere is it specified
我不能把这项义务外包给印度人
that I can't outsource that to an Indian.
华仔
Howie?
我美丽的新娘子
Hey, there's my beautiful bride!
你可以看见我吗
Can you see me?
可以  你还好吗
I can. How are you?
棒极了
I'm amazing.
而且是比我梦想中的还要棒
I mean, this is even better than I dreamed.
当我看出窗外  一切都是那么难以置信
I look out the window, and... it's all so unbelievable.
那就好
Good for you.
我刚跟你妈吃了一顿没完没了的晚餐
I just had a seemingly endless dinner with your mom.
是吗  那不错啊
Oh, yeah? That's nice.
一开始还不错  直到我发现你没告诉她
It was. Until I found out you never told her
我们要搬出去住
we're not gonna live with her.
咱们来好好聊聊这件事吧
Let's talk about that for a minute.
快看  这根笔在飘浮耶
Hey, look, this pen is floating.
很不可思议吧
How crazy is that?
你说过会告诉她  可你没有
You said you told her, but you never did!
好吧  我知道你很失望  可...
Okay, okay, I know you're upset, but...
不如我跟你分享下  我来这学到的道理吧
let me share something I've learned since I got here.
当你从太空中往下看地球时
You realize how small your problems are
你会意识到自己的难题  根本微不足道
when you're looking down on them from space.
拜托  听完之后应该开心点了吧
Now, come on, that's got to make you feel better.
你在屏幕上看我有多清晰呀
How clear is the image of me on that screen?
蛮清晰的
Pretty clear.
我看起来像有开心点吗
Do I look like I feel better?
也没有到高清画质啦
I mean, it's not, like, HD quality.
你给我听好了  快去跟你妈妈说
Listen, mister, you're gonna talk to your mother
把这件事给老娘处理好  不然之前答应你
and you're gonna fix this, or that thing I said
你一回家就给你的"服务"
I was gonna do to you the minute you got home,
你就准备"自己来"吧
you can do to yourself.
打从他上太空  就没少"来"过
Like he's been doing since he got here.
谢尔顿  这地方好浪漫啊
Sheldon, this place is so romantic.
很高兴你喜欢
Oh, I'm glad you like it.
是拉杰选的
Raj picked it out.
你下次看见他  帮我说声谢谢
Well, when you see him, tell him I say thank you.
你可以自己跟他说
Tell him yourself.
这边这边
Over here!
我不懂  他在这里干嘛
I don't understand. What's he doing here?
是我邀请他的
I invited him.
来当电灯泡吗
On our date?
谢尔顿  这样属于违约
Sheldon, that's not okay.
才没有
Yes, it is.
我们的恋爱协议有个漏洞
There's a loophole in the Relationship Agreement.
你居然发现了个漏洞
You found a loophole?
抱歉我先点了  我有点小紧张
Sorry I started without you. I'm a little nervous.
我很久没约过会了
It's been a long time since I've been on a date.
真不敢相信我居然为了今天  漂白了胡子
I can't believe I bleached my mustache for this.
你应该找我那个美容师
You should go to my girl.
她还能免费帮你把鬓脚修掉
She'll knock out those sideburns for free.
艾米  我觉得
You know, Amy, I don't even think
我们俩都没好好聊过
you and I have had a real conversation.
不如今晚就让我们加深对彼此的了解吧
Let's use tonight to get to know each other a little better.
你先开始
You start.
滚回家
Go home.
我没听懂
I don't understand.
谢尔顿  你怎么能这样呢
Sheldon, how could you do this?
这是我们的两周年纪念日
It's our second anniversary.
今天是你们的纪念日啊
It's your anniversary?!
天啊  我真的不知道
Oh, my God, I had no idea.
艾米  拜托让我将功补过
Amy, please, let me make this right.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我的荣幸  服务员
My pleasure. Waiter?
香槟一瓶  杯子三个
A bottle of champagne and three glasses.
天啊  这是不是很浪漫呀
Oh, boy, isn't this romantic?
我希望这是个反问句
Oh, I hope that's a rhetorical question,
因为我真不知道浪不浪漫
because I have no clue.
真棒  今天是什么日子
This is great. What's the occasion?
什么都不是
No occasion.
你也知道  我们最近关系有点怪怪的
You know, things have been a little weird between us,
所以我想为你准备一个开心的夜晚
so I wanted to throw together a fun night just for you.
-太贴心了  -我准备了你爱吃的
- That is so sweet. - I got all your favorites.
啤酒  鸡翅  小汉堡
Beer, wings, sliders.
我们可以看橄榄球比赛
We can watch the football game.
我还在我肚皮上写字了呢
I even painted my stomach.
"体育万岁"
"Go sports"?
以防你突然想换成看棒球
in case you were in the mood for baseball,
这样我什么球赛都可以加油到
I didn't want to look ridiculous.
这太棒了  我超喜欢的
This is awesome. I love it!
你开心我也开心
Good, I'm glad.
天啊  我今天累死了
Gosh, I worked my ass off today.
正好需要轻松一下
This is exactly what I needed.
太棒了  那放松享受吧
Great. Just relax and enjoy.
今晚你就是主角
Tonight is all about you.
谢谢你
Ah, thank you!
所以我俩之间的关系到底算是什么状况
So, where exactly are we in this relationship?
唉  你又来了
Oh, come on!
我刚跟你说了今天很累
I just told you I had a hard day.
对对  我错了  看球看球
You're right, I'm sorry. Let's watch the game.
对嘛
Great.
但这事拖越久不谈只会变得更尴尬
I just know the longer we wait to talk about it, the weirder it gets.
亲爱的  我今晚就不能做个幸福小女生吗
Sweetie, can I just be the girl tonight?
当然可以  你是小女生  我是小男孩
Absolutely. You're the girl, I'm the guy.
那你看球
Now, you watch your football game
-我给你盛碟好吃的  -谢谢
- while I make you a little plate here. - Thank you!
我来开
Oh, I'll get it.
体育万岁
Go sports!
你好哟
Hello-lo-lo.
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
你不是跟谢尔顿和艾米在一起吗
I thought you were out th Sheldon and Amy.
本来是的  但这是人家周年纪念
I was, but it's their anniversary
我不想当电灯泡
and I didn't want to be a third wheel,
所以就想着来这儿
so I figured I'd come over here
参合你和佩妮的约会
and hang out with you and Penny on your date.
现在不大方便
Well, it's not really a great time.
佩妮和我要谈些事情
Penny and I have some things we need to talk about.
才不呢  进来吧
No, we don't! Come on in!
真棒
Sweet!
难以置信  我居然为了这个把肚皮上的毛给刮了
I can't believe I shaved my stomach for this.
嘿  果麦圈客
Hey, Froot Loops.
有电话找
You got a phone call.
谁啊
Who is it?
说是你妈
A woman who says she's your mother
听像你爸
but sounds like your father.
妈
Hey, Ma.
如果你把电脑打开的话
You know, we could see each other
我们其实可以看到对方的
if you turn on the computer.
我才不会接近那坨垃圾呢
I'm not going near that fakakta thing.
我会感染电脑病毒的
I'll catch a computer virus!
你是不会感染电脑病毒的
You can't catch a computer virus.
所以你现在既是宇航员还是医生了吗
Oh, so now you're an astronaut and a doctor?
你想说啥啊  妈
What do you want, Ma?
你老婆说你有重要事情告诉我
Your wife says you have something important to tell me.
好吧  是这样
Okay, here it is.
伯纳黛特和我要开始共同生活  然后
Bernadette and I are starting a life together and...
老天啊  你要弃我而去啦
Oh, God! You are gonna leave me!
妈
Ma...
没关系的
It's okay.
你爸离开我  你也这样
Your father left me, you left me--
我就是那种别人想要抛弃的人
I guess I'm just the kind of person people like to leave.
这不...还没定呢
It's not... definite.
我会和伯纳黛特商量的
I'll talk to Bernadette.
不用你废心了
Don't bother.
我还是地上挖个坑住着
I'll just go sit in a hole in the ground
死了也省事儿
so I'm no trouble when I die.
别说了  妈
Stop it, Ma.
我肯定能带着小妮妮常回家看看的
I'm sure I can get Bernie to come around.
我就知道
I knew it!
她是幕后黑手
I knew she was behind this!
你听着  要当纯爷们儿
You listen to me, if you want to be a man,
你就不能让女人对你指手划脚
you can't let a woman tell you what to do!
好了好了
Okay, okay.
难以置信  这些人居然赢了冷战
I can't believe these people won the Cold War.
现在你能换个话题吗
Now, can we please change the subject?
好吧
Fine.
那你给我解释解释为啥走了这么久
Explain why you've been gone so long
我没收到过一封信
and I haven't gotten a single letter.
连张便宜明信片都没有
Not even a lousy postcard!
我开始越来越喜欢橄榄球了
You know, I'm growing to like American football.
挺有意思的对吧么
Yeah, it's fun, isn't it?
虽然没羽毛球或板球这么热血[印度热门运动]
Well...it's not the balls-to-the-wall action of badminton or cricket,
不过嘛
but hey...
也不必那么苛求
what is?
好吧  谁还要再来一瓶啤酒
All right, who's ready for another beer?
-我还有  -不用了  谢谢
- I'm good.  - No, thank you.
娘炮
Girls.
这是我最美好的时光
I am having the nicest time.
你们就像我的家人
You guys are like family to me.
你懂的  对吧
You know that, right?
很好  滚吧
That's great. Get out.
为什么
What? Why?
佩妮和我有些事儿需要谈谈
Penny and I have some issues we need to talk about.
屁大的事儿啊
Pish on your issues!
你们没问题的
You guys are fine.
没错  你一路上是遇到了点障碍
Yes, you hit some bumps along the way.
还有  佩妮
I mean, Penny,
你也知道这个男人对你的感情
you've always known how this man has felt about you,
但你却总让他祈求你的关爱
but you made him grovel for affection.
等等
Okay, hold on...
别内疚
Now, don't blame yourself.
他从来都是祈求者
He was a groveler from way back.
但我的意思是  你们俩总要跨过去的
But the point is, the two of you got past it.
莱纳德  你滚床单滚一半
And, Leonard, you go and propose
对这可怜的女娃求婚
to this poor girl in the middle of sex?
实在是弱爆了  老兄
That was some weak tea, dude.
有些人也许会觉得浪漫呢
Some people might say it was romantic.
不可能
Yeah, no.
但你看你俩现在还在一起
But yet, here you two are, still together.
甚至还是在我俩激情一裸的那晚之后
And that's even after you and I had our crazy naked night.
够了够了
Okay... That's enough.
我是说
I'm just saying
在你俩同甘共苦这么久之后
that after everything you've been through,
总能互相凝望
you get to look into each other's eyes
说声"我爱你"
and say "I love you."
这是多么的美好
And that's beautiful.
事实上到现在为止她还没说过
Actually, to this day, she's never really said it.
佩妮  这太荒谬了
Oh, Penny! That's ridiculous!
你心里知道你爱她的
You know you love him!
你看着他的眼睛然后说出来
You look him in the eyes and you say it.
-拉杰  -别这样
- Raj...  - Oh, come on,
你知道你想说的  说出来吧
you know you want to say it. Say it.
说你爱他
Say you love him.
快说啊
Say it!
我真以为她一定会说呢
I really thought she would say it.
我有没有跟你说过你像性感的螳螂
Have I ever told you you're like a sexy praying mantis?
每次喝了酒你都会说
Every time you drink alcohol.
你知道螳螂的妙处在哪里吗
You know what's wonderful about the praying mantis?
它们会吃掉自己的配偶
They devour their mate.
你意思是...
Your point being?
"甜点"上桌
Dessert is served.
我刚吃完果馅饼呢
I just had cobbler.
知道吗
You know what?
我受够了
I'm done with this.
你去哪里啊
W-Where are you going?
我走人
I'm leaving.
你不能走
You can't leave.
我需要你
I need you.
你需要我吗
You do?
是的
Yes.
你是我的司机
You're my ride.
谢尔顿  你最好真心地说些甜言蜜语
Sheldon, you either say something meaningful
不然咱俩就此结束
and from the heart, or you and I are done.
好吧
All right.
请坐
Please.
艾米
Amy...
当我看着你的双眼
when I look in your eyes
而你也深情看着我时
and you're looking back in mine,
一切都好像变得特别了
everything feels not quite normal,
因为我
because I feel
感觉自己变得更强大  同时也更软弱
stronger and weaker at the same time.
我感到激情澎湃的同时  也胆战心惊
I feel excited and, at the same time, terrified.
事实是
The truth is,
我不知道自己的真实感觉  但是
I don't know what I feel, except...
我知道自己想做一个怎样的男人
I know what kind of man I want to be.
谢尔顿
Sheldon...
我好感动
that was beautiful.
我也希望有这效果
I should hope so.
这是《蜘蛛侠I》里的经典台词
That's from the first Spider-Man movie.
我受领了
I'll take it.
很好
Good.
现在  咱俩该分摊饭钱了吧
Now, I assume we're splitting the check?
斯图尔特
Hey, Stuart.
来啦  我正准备打烊
Oh, hey. I was actually just about to close up.
不好意思  我这就走
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll leave.
不用  没事  随便看
No, no. It's okay. Hang out.
这样好吗
You sure?
没关系  你是今天我这里的头位顾客
Yeah, you're my first customer today.
好的  太好了
All right. Great.
我正准备来点睡前小酒
I'm, uh, having a nightcap.
要一起来一杯吗
You want to join me?
你喝的是什么
What are you drinking?
用楚巴卡马克杯喝咖啡利口酒
Coffee liqueur in a Chewbacca mug.
我管这个叫"悲催马天尼"
I call it a sad-tini.
我今晚喝这个正应景  多谢
Perfect for the night I'm having. Thank you.
有人陪着喝酒感觉真好
Hmm. Nice not to drink alone.
那还用说
Amen to that.
有时候我会往
Sometimes I pour
我家小狗的水碗里倒点霞多丽葡萄酒
a little chardonnay into my dog's water bowl.
真的假的
You're kidding.
它喝醉了有点难缠  但总比独醉得好
She's kind of a mean drunk, but what are you gonna do?
干杯
Cheers.
-来点音乐助兴  -好啊
- A little music? - Sure.
芭沙风情[新派爵士乐]
Bossa nova.
听这个要用耳朵和屁股一起感受
You listen to that with your hips as well as your ears.
正是
Mmm.
拉丁风情的音乐里
Something about...
那种调调能让我陶醉到
Latin music just makes me feel like
犹如置身里约热内卢的白沙滩
I'm on a white sand beach in Rio.
没错
Yeah.
艳阳  波涛  娇躯
The sun, the waves, the beautiful bodies,
麦色的皮肤  晶莹的汗水
tanned and glistening with sweat.
-我该走了  -不送了
- I should go. - Yeah.
谢谢你请我喝酒
Uh, thank you for the drink.
甭客气
No problem.
-斯图尔特  -啥事儿
- Hey, Stuart. - Yeah?
你想不想  明晚咱们出去玩玩
Do you want to... hang out tomorrow night,
一起吃个饭  看个晚场电影什么的
maybe grab a bite to eat or catch a late movie?
我很乐意  但我手头有点紧
Yeah, I-I'd like to, but I'm a little tight on funds.
没事  我请客
No problem. My treat.
我下班后过来
I'll swing by after work.
好的
Okay.
说定了
我还能更没下限一点
I could do worse.
这真是个好消息  华仔
Aw, that's such good news, Howie.
多谢你告诉她
Thank you for telling her.
我可是男子汉  当然得跟老婆一起住了
Hey, I'm a grown man; I'm gonna live with my wife.
我老妈只能学着接受一个人过日子了
My mother's just gonna have to learn to make do on her own.
她生气了吗
Was she upset?
谁知道啊  怒吼是她的正常语气
Who can tell? She yells everything.
她可能生气了
She might have been upset.
她可能是饿了
She might have been hungry.
多谢你搞定这事
Thanks for fixing it.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
做个好梦哦  明天再聊
Sweet dreams. I'll talk to you tomorrow?
晚安  火箭男
Good night, Rocket Man.
飞向宇宙  浩瀚无垠  宝贝[巴斯光年名句]
To infinity and beyond, baby.
圈客
Loops.
你知道自己现在是老妈老婆
You realize you just lied your ass off
两头瞒吗
to your wife and your mother.
我知道
I know.
你回到地球后打算咋办
What are you gonna do when you get back to Earth?
瞧你说的  我在这儿安家了
Oh, I'm never going back.